STEPHANE YENI NOUKIE

DevOps Engineer/Cloud Engineer Phone: (346) 370 6692 | Warren, MI 48091

Email: nyenistephane2@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/stephane-yeni

SUMMARY

Highly skilled and motivated DevOps Engineer with 5+ Years of experience specializing in continuous integration, deployment, automation, and cloud technologies. Proficient in designing and implementing CI/CD pipelines using tools such as Jenkins, and GitLab resulting in significant reductions in deployment time and increased development efficiency. Experienced in managing infrastructure as code using Terraform and Ansible, automating the provisioning and configuration of cloud resources to ensure scalability, reliability, and cost-effectiveness.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

★ Cloud Platforms: AWS: EC2, CloudWatch, IAM, S3

★ Configuration Management: Ansible

★ Containerization: Kubernetes★ Version Control: Git, GitHub

★ Monitoring: Splunk★ Scripting: Bash★ CI/CD: Jenkins

★ Infrastructure as Code: Terraform

★ Operating Systems: Linux (Ubuntu, CentOS) Windows server

★ Collaboration Tools: JIRA, Confluence, Slack★ Programming language: python, Java, html

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Cloud Operation /DevOps Engineer At iCare Medical Role and Responsibilities:

Sep.2021 - present

- ★ For faster and more reliable software delivery, I established a CI/CD pipeline using Jenkinsfile, Which automated continuous integration tasks from code commits to testing, reduced manual Effort and improved collaboration between development and operations teams for multiple projects, Improving code Quality reducing security vulnerability and defects.
- ★ Proficient in the development and management of build, test, artifacts and deployment scripts, Tailored for test, staging and production environments, leveraging build tool like Maven, and Docker builds scripting technologies.
- ★ To ensure high availability, improved performance, and secure delivery of web content I hosted secure static websites on AWS, leveraging services such as S3, Cloudfront, AWS Lambda, Amazon EC2, AWS Certificate Manager and more.

- ★ For reducing manual effort and improving operational efficiency, maintaining consistent configurations and enabling faster deployment of infrastructure resources, i automated infrastructure provisioning using tools such as Terraform and Ansible.
 - To improve resource utilization and reduce infrastructure costs, I used containerization such as Docker And managed deployment with kubernetes
- ★ I played a vital role in reducing operational costs by 30% improving scalability, and enabling the adoption of cloud-native services and elastic resource provisioning via coordination of the migration of on-premises infrastructure to the cloud.
- ★ To streamline infrastructure management tasks, ensure consistency across environment and Reduce human errors.
 - Collaborated closely with the development team to troubleshoot and resolve technical issues, ensuring seamless build and deployment processes.

Linux System Administrator Engineer At DR Financial Services Role and Responsibilities: Dec.2019 - Sep. 2021

- ★ Experience with Linux operating systems including installing, configuring and troubleshooting
- ★ To achieve high availability and system reliability, managed and maintained Linux servers (CentOs ,Red Hat,Ubuntu, Debian) in various environments. configuring and updating software packages, and patches on Linux servers requested by the Users.
- ★ I successfully achieved a 30% reduction in manual effort and a significant increase in operational efficiency by automating routine tasks using bash shell scripting.

 Experience in setting up an Haproxy, LAMP STACK.
- ★ Administered and maintained Linux servers, ensuring optimal performance and security.
- ★ Desire, passion and ability of learning, growth and developed troubleshooting passion.

Quality Engineer at webasto Role and Responsibilities:

Feb.2018 - Dec 2019

- ★ Developing and Implementing QA processes
- ★ Ensuring Supplier Quality and Ensuring Customer Satisfaction

CERTIFICATION

★ CKA : Certified Kubernetes Administrator In process

EDUCATION

★ GED

Language: Proficient in written and verbal communication in both English and French